ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
潇湘月影
翻译
煮粥达人
木浅
翻译
showeryhe
滚成一个团子
翻译
冬麟
时间轴
Kallen   今   兜兜兜爹
特效
宝宝
电脑狂人
第二季
第三集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
不错
Nice.
程序战士
Hey, code warrior.
孩子们准备好了
The girls are ready.
你趴在抄本上睡着了
You fell asleep on your transcripts.
肯定做怪梦了吧
Must've made for some creepy dreams.
这叫市场调查
Hey, it's market research.
你知道你们的网络为什么出问题吗
You know why your network's on the fritz...
有人蹭网
freeloaders. Ghosts.
-我们知道有多少用户  -合法用户
- We know how many subscribers we have. - Legit ones.
而蹭网的人占用了你们的带宽
Meanwhile, the cheats gobble up your bandwidth.
如果有人能写一个程序
But what if someone were to write a program
找到全部用户
to find all your users
描绘出你们实际的用户分布呢
and map the actual size of your network?
我称之为索纳里斯
I call it Sonaris.
听听这个  你对美苏关系的见解
Listen to this: "Your understanding of U.S.-Soviet relations
就如有白内障的狐猴一样短浅
is as shortsighted as a lemur with cataracts."
他们管这叫"网络论战"
They call it a "Flame war."
唐娜  我写这个程序可是为了你
Donna, you realize I'm doing this for you, you know?
-我知道  -你能不能...
- Yeah, I know. - Could you at...
你一定很投入
And you must really be enjoying it
因为我都两周没见你了
because I haven't seen you for two weeks.
你能看看吗  好吗
Okay, well, will you take a look, okay?
我快写完了
I'm almost done.
-说说看  -什么
- But tell me something. - What?
谁是你的超人
Who's your Superman?
露易丝
Huh, Lois?
分别是《超人》女主和超人
-露易丝·莱恩  -克拉克
- Lois Lane. - Oh, Clark.
想假装咱俩在电话亭里[超人变身]吗
Wanna pretend we're in a phone booth?
天呐
Oh, God.
记得让琼妮喝果汁
Just don't let Joanie forget her juice.
等等  我还没穿斗篷呢
Wait, I'll wear the cape!
看  我把眼镜戴上了  你喜欢我戴眼镜的
Hey, glasses on. You like it with the glasses.
渺小的凡人
Puny earthling.
-车拿去修了吗  -是啊
- Is your car in the shop? - Yep.
自行车不错
Nice wheels.
有喇叭吗
Does it have a horn?
一定是落家里了  还有我的小丑鼻子
Must've left it at home with my clown nose.
你把她弄回来了
You got... you got her back.
房子给了靳妮
Well, Ginnie got the house,
其余的都归了公
Feds got everything else.
除了这辆车
Oh, but not this.
天呐
Whoo, God.
真是太谢谢你了  巴瑞
Can't thank you enough, Barry.
-你和露易丝...  -乐意效劳
- You and Louise... - Glad to.
帮我留住车  让我借住
holding on to this, putting me up,
保护我不被生吞活剥
keeping the jackals at bay.
而你给了我二十年的饭碗
And you put food on my table for, what, 20 years?
我该怎么报答你
Anything I can do to repay you?
你可以上车  像个爷们儿一样把车开走
You can get in that tank and drive it like a man.
好
All right.
这就对了
There you go.
棒
Yeah!
是啊
Yeah.
-适应新工作了吗  -适应了
- Settling in? - I am.
-谢谢  尤金  -不客气
- Thanks, Eugene. - Fine, that's just fine.
不过我有几个点子
I've got some ideas, though.
我们复查这些文件避免扫描错误
We double-check all these documents for scanning errors.
-是啊  -我有时候会发现
- Yes, sir. - And sometimes I'll notice a correlation
油井的钻孔深度和抽取速率有关
between a well's perforation level and its drainage rate
我会把它记在这儿
and I'll make a note of it here.
如果我们都做记录
And if we all took those notes,
就可以把数据录入电子表格
we could harvest them into spreadsheets,
-也许就能发现...  -数据处理
- maybe find some... - Data processing...
-怎么了  -在地下一层
- Yeah? - ...is on B1.
这里是数据录入部
This is data entry.
看见那主机了吗  我们的工作是填满它
That mainframe in there? Our job is to fill it up.
铲沙子而不是数谷子
Shovel sand, not count the grains.
-你不觉得有问题吗  -不觉得
- And that doesn't bother you? - No.
我知道盯着60年的井深数据看
Listen, I know staring at 60 years of well depths
不是刺激的工作
ain't exactly hair-raising.
所以最好有点消遣活动
That's why it helps to have a pastime.
我们在举行诱饵装饰比赛
We're doing a decoy decorating contest.
公鸭或母鸡  随你挑
Drakes or hens, your choice.
我收集老式打击乐器
I myself... I collect vintage percussion.
这个周末  我有幸购得了
This weekend, I was fortunate to obtain
备受狄托·庞特[拉丁爵士大师]喜爱的天巴鼓
a timbale favored by the great Tito Puente.
来点咖啡吗
Do you want some coffee?
一双大手不断靠近抢夺你美味的果冻
Giant hands keep reaching and grabbing for your tasty Jell-O chunks.
点子
但是你躲开了
But you dodge them,
上上下下  一层又一层
up, down, shelf to shelf.
很快  冰箱就空了
Soon the fridge is empty.
只有你  果冻碗幸免于难
Only you, the Jell-O bowl, have survived.
我管它叫"摇摇乐"
I call it "Jiggles."
挺好  大家有什么问题吗
Cool, uh, questions, anyone?
-那果冻什么味的  -当然是橘子味
- Uh, what flavor the Jell-O? - Orange, obviously.
-摇摇乐听着像脱衣舞俱乐部  -不是的
- "Jiggles" Sounds like a strip joint. - Well, it's not.
只有我支持那双手吗
Am I the only one that's rooting for the hands?
因为这家人饿了  你又可以吃
You know, 'cause the family's hungry and you're available.
我觉得你就该被吃掉
I feel like it's your job to be eaten, you know?
除非你腐臭发霉了  放了三周了
Unless you're rancid, moldy, like three weeks old.
那你可以管这叫
Yeah, and then you could call it, like,
"吃必死果冻"或者什么的
"Jell-O Death Wish" or something.
你的任务是毒死这家人  杀了他们
Your mission ... poison the family. Kill 'em all.
-太对了  -我的果冻没有腐烂
- Totally. - My Jell-O is not rancid.
好了  大家都歇会儿吧
Okay, let's just let it breathe for a second.
谢谢你  莱夫
Thanks, Lev.
汤姆
Uh, Tom.
有什么点子吗
Ideas?
嗯  我在调整精灵单元的大小适应背景
Yeah, I'm working on sprite scaling for immersive environments.
悬浮在每帧游戏画面之外的图形单元
好  有故事吗
Okay, does it have a story?
-需要故事吗  -对  会有帮助
- Does it need one? - Uh, yeah, it helps.
在线游戏与游戏厅或卡带游戏不同
Online gaming is different from arcade or cartridge.
你要把玩家吸引到一个世界里
You're trying to draw the players into a world,
-而不只是骗他们投币  -你开玩笑吗
- not just hustle them for quarters... - Are you joking?
无数游戏都以技术突破为卖点
Tons of titles have started with tech breakthroughs.
《太空战机》《空间逃脱》
"Xevious," "Zaxxon"...
好  我们私下聊行吗
Okay, let's just talk about it in private, yeah?
谢谢[俄语]
Ah, spasibo.
-这是新游戏吗  -对  视差第22章
- This something new? - Yeah, "Parallax," Chapter 22.
刚出炉的  我们先玩几天
Hot off the presses, so let's take a couple days to play with it,
再调试更新到网络上
then we will debug and load it onto the network.
-可以吗  -可以
- Sound good? - Yeah.
-行吗  -行  好
- Sound good? - Yes. Cool.
*岩岛线  好路线*
*Rock Island Line, it's the road to ride*
*岩岛线是条好路线*
*Rock Island Line is a mighty good road*
*你若走岩岛线  得有点新鲜感*
*Well, if you ride it, you gotta ride it like you find it*
*拿上票  走岩岛线*
*Get your ticket at the station for the Rock Island Line*
*我也许对  也许错*
*Oh, I may be right and I may be wrong*
*但我离开后你会想念我*
*But you're gonna miss me when I'm gone*
*驾驶员死前说*
*Well, the engineer said before he died*
*还想再喝两杯*
*There are two more drinks that he'd like to try*
*你若走岩岛线  得有点新鲜感*
*But if you wanna ride it, gotta ride it like you find it*
*拿上票  走岩岛线*
*Get your ticket at the station for the Rock Island Line*
你迟到了
You're late.
怎么  我让你别的男朋友都久等了吗
Oh, what, I make all your other boyfriends hang fire?
让他们等
They can wait.
喂
Hello?
-怎么早了  -我的扫描仪分不清
- You're early. - My scanner can't tell the difference
小写的I和L
between lower case Is and Ls.
你知道最多的词是什么吗
Do you know what every other word is?
-油  -油吗
- Oil. - Oil?
我呢  已经盯着窗外无所事事一小时了
Me, I've spent the past hour looking out the window.
至少你还有个窗户
At least you have one.
搬来这里是错误吗
Was moving here a mistake?
也许吧
Uh, probably.
真好  那我今晚就收拾行李
Oh, great. I'm gonna go pack tonight.
莎拉  我开玩笑的  我们不能回奥斯汀
Sara, it was a joke. We can't go back to Austin.
你父亲一定会气疯的
Your father would flip.
是  我知道
No, I... I know, I know.
我爱我父亲  但是管他呢
And, look, I love my dad, but screw him, you know?
天哪  真不敢相信我在抱怨
Oh, God, I can't believe I'm whining.
我讨厌自己抱怨的样子
I hate when I get like this.
我们一起吃个晚饭吧
Let's have dinner.
邀上朋友办个晚宴
A dinner party with other people.
有免费晚餐埃文和艾丽西娅一定愿意来
Evan and Alicia will drive up for a free meal, right?
你也可以邀请你在达拉斯的朋友
You could invite your friends from Dallas.
你不愿意就算了
Unless that makes you uncomfortable.
没有  会很好玩的
No, that... um, that sounds like fun.
再打给你
Let me get back to you.
你打的是私人电话吗
Is that a personal call?
我爱你
Love you.
雅各布·维勒在吗  我是乔·麦克米伦
Is Jacob Wheeler in? Joe MacMillan.
我想做个预约
Yes, I'd like to make an appointment.
4点吗  可以  我没问题
4:00? Absolutely, that works for me.
到时候见
I'll see you then.
只要能上网  人们什么都聊
Give people a dial-up, they'll talk about anything...
政治  体育  超模凯茜·爱尔兰
politics, sports, Kathy Ireland,
比利·乔唱得烂
Billy Joel sucks...
比利的歌挺好的
Hey, Billy has chops.
我发起了一个关于穆格电子琴的讨论
I started a discussion on Moog synthesizers.
居然有23条回复  我想借位程序员
It got 23 replies. Can I borrow a coder?
我们得把社区分化
We need to split Community into multiple forms.
-都快挤炸了  -可以
- It's exploding. - Yes, okay.
把莱夫带走吧
Take Lev, please.
-在线用户有多少  -306
- Hey, how many online? - 306.
-什么  -是啊
- What? - Yeah.
这是涨了多少  一周50吗
That's up, what, 50, week to week?
坦克大战要腥风血雨了
It's gonna be a bloodbath in "Tank Battle."
这就是我们商业模式的最大优点
Well, that's the beautiful thing about our business model.
人人都想玩一把
Even the corpses pay to play.
交换机软件挺好用的
That PBX patch is holding.
我们算脱离困境了吧
So we're above water.
只是稍有改善而已
Well, we're just not drowning so fast.
我选了条新长距离航线
I picked up a new long-haul route.
是吗
Oh, you did?
终点是哪啊
Where's the layover?
-东京  -啊呀呀
- Tokyo. - Ah, me "wrikey."
东京啊
Tokyo.
我们这个小秘密恐怕要叫停了
It's gonna put a serious hitch in these little hanky-panks.
那我去找你就行了
I'll just stop by the house.
我不建议你这么做
I wouldn't.
那今天这是什么意思
Well, what's this about, then?
这是
This...
我当初嫁给你的原因
is why I married you in the first place.
25B座位的男人
The man in 25B.
要拉下脸了吗
Going dark on me?
没关系
It's okay.
房子是我付的钱
Well, I paid for that house.
但现在是我的了
And now it's mine.
我想跟谁做什么都行
And I can do what I want with whom I want.
我理解  我只是不想觉得
I understand that. I just don't want to feel
我是被扫地出门了
that there's a broom at my heels.
你在牢里的时候世界没有因此停滞
The world didn't stop when you went to prison.
你嫌弃我吗  靳妮
You ashamed of me, Ginnie?
现在不了
Not anymore.
好吧  那周末见
All right, well, I'll see you this weekend, then.
但愿你是在说笑
I hope you're joking.
我只是觉得那个时机不合适
I just don't think the time's right.
慢着  你今天来就为了这个吗
Well, hold on, now. Is that why you showed up today?
说服我不要去加尔维斯顿
To convince me not to go to Galveston?
说实话  我没觉得还得我说
Honestly, I didn't think I'd have to.
我们都不再是你的卫星了
We're not your satellites anymore,
绕着老大飞来飞去
spinning around the big man.
这一路走来很有趣  很精彩
It was a fun ride and a real hot show,
但这次主角不是你
but this one's not yours.
拜托别来  约翰
Please don't come, John.
保证你不会来
Promise you won't.
回头告诉我
Let me know.
向南希和孩子们代好
Love to Nancy and the kids.
再见
All right.
有些人就是不想得到拯救
Some people don't want to be saved.
知道自杀者最常见的最后时刻遗憾是什么吗
You know the most common last-second regret of suicides?
那些跳桥但幸存的人
People who jump off bridges but live?
高中时的女友
High school girlfriends.
水龙头忘关了
Faucet left on.
车没停好  冰箱没关  未尽的事
Car running. Fridge open. Just loose ends.
好吧  有话直说
Okay, let me have it.
你在流失数据  那些数据能用来
You're leaking data, data that can be used to
增加产量  预测收益  降低风险
increase yields, predict profits, reduce risk.
我建议把数据的收集
I suggest folding data collection
和分析合并成一个部门
and analytics into a single department...
-好啊  做吧  -我还没说完
- Sure, do it. - I'm not done.
我说完了
I am.
下面谁负责
Who's in charge down there?
尤金·鲍迪奇
Uh, Eugene Bowdich.
炒了他  把整个部门都废了
Fire him. Scrap the whole department.
自己新建  这样最好
Build your own. It's the best way.
我会跟人力资源说
I'll let HR know.
没想到你愿意待在地下层
I never thought you'd stay on the basement level,
但如果那就是你的目标
but if that's your goal...
我还要几天来准备
I just need a few days to prepare.
去吧
Take 'em.
乔
Joe?
拥挤的火车上有了空位
Seat opens up on a crowded train.
犹豫一下也没关系  也许你下一站就到了
It's okay to hesitate. Maybe you're the next stop.
也许你是个大善人
Maybe you're a good Samaritan.
也许你觉得自己配不上
Or maybe you think you don't deserve it.
就是这样  周四晚8点
So, that's it. Thursday night, 8:00.
希望你们能来  见面再谈
Hope you guys can make it. Talk soon.
我想再听一次
Okay, I just need to listen to it one more time.
我想邀请你们来
I'd love it if you could come by
跟我和我未婚妻共进晚餐
for a little dinner party with me and my fiancé.
-未婚妻  -我幻听了吗
- Fiancé? - Am I hallucinating?
你先说
Okay, you first.
我想是个香水模特
Okay, I'm picturing a perfume model.
迪奥  不  是候司顿
Dior... no, no, no, Halston.
-高个  金发  -必然的
- Tall, blonde... - Well, duh.
达丽尔·汉纳[女演员]的颧骨  有垫肩  上东区
Daryl Hannah cheekbones, shoulder pads, Upper East Side.
不  卡梅伦之后他肯定想要个追随者
No, no, no, no, no. After Cameron, he'd want a follower.
没那么难搞的人
You know, someone less challenging.
-真的  -没错
- Really? - Yeah.
对我适用
Worked for me.
我觉得是个秘书  琼·贝兹[民歌歌手]那种
I'm going with a secretary, Joan Baez type.
垫子上印猫咪那种小女生
You know, kittens on the futon.
我们去就知道了
I guess we'll find out.
怎么  去赴他的晚餐吗
What? Dinner? With him?
当然  拜托  你不好奇吗
Well, yeah. Oh, come on. Aren't you curious?
神奇的是  我对高大阴沉
Mysteriously, my interest in tall, dark mannequins
自以为是的假人没什么兴趣了
with delusions of grandeur has dwindled,
但是  你自便吧
but, hey, knock yourself out.
势利眼
Snob.
冤大头
Sucker.
你们好  戈登  唐娜
Hey, Gordon and Donna.
我是乔  乔·麦克米伦
It's Joe. Joe MacMillan.
好了  尝尝苦头吧
That's it, taste the pain.
下跪  在佐德面前下跪吧
Now, kneel. Kneel before Zod.
此句为《超人》电影台词
保姆到了  姑娘们在搭城堡呢
Hey, babysitter's here. Girls are building a fort.
你个扭曲的小娘们
Oh, you twisted little mother.
你说什么
Excuse me?
没错  亲爱的...好  亲爱的
Yes, dear... I mean, yes, honey.
该死  有个蹭网的把我毙了
Damn it. One of your freeloaders just wasted me.
好吧  我要去冲澡了
Okay, well, I'm gonna go shower.
我们要无意地故意迟到
I want us accidentally late on purpose.
我们能不去吗  我觉得我要感冒了
Can't we bag? I think I feel a cold coming on.
戈登  这是你的主意
Gordon, this was your idea.
那就我们俩出去怎么样
Well, how about the two of us just go out?
去丛林俱乐部  火把俱乐部
You know, Chaparral Club, the Torch, you know?
我们叫萝丝留下过夜  在市里开个房
We'll tell Rose to stay the night, maybe rent a room downtown.
我很乐意  听上去不错
I would love to. That sounds great.
但我们告诉他们要去的
But we told them we're coming.
20分钟后出发
Wheels up in 20.
此段借用《超人》台词
卡尔-艾尔为超人本名
他们能成为伟大的种族  卡尔-艾尔
"They can be a great people, Kal-El;
索纳里斯
如果他们想的话
they wish to be."
他们只是缺少
They only lack the program
指路的程序罢了
to show them the way.
索纳里斯
Sonaris.
我感觉不错
Plays good for me.
我也是
Me, too.
谢谢
Thanks.
我喜欢吸血鱼妞
I like the vampire fish ladies.
是海妖
Oh, yeah, the sea nymphs.
我想不出陆上生物了  所以我...
Uh, I ran out of land-based creatures, so I...
汤姆  你玩了游戏了吗
Tom, did you play the game?
玩了
Yeah.
你觉得呢
And?
我们私下谈好吗
Let's talk about it in private, okay?
不  我们就在这里谈
Uh, no, we all have a voice here.
你觉得怎么样
What did you think?
好吧
Okay.
我通关大概花了一个半小时
It took me about an hour and a half.
-挺快的  -因为这是旧瓶装新酒
- That's pretty fast. - Because it's a rehash.
你借用了第9章的布局
You stole the layout from chapter nine
第14章的谜题  把它们混在一起
and the puzzles from fourteen, you put them in a blender
-希望没人能注意到  -不  我
- and hoped no one would notice. - No, I...
还有  如果你被困  那个毛茸茸的灯罩
And of course if you get stuck, the hairy lampshade
就会跑进来  直接...
comes swooping in and literally...
那是毡帽
What? It's a fez.
把线索像头皮屑一样抖到你头上
...drops clues on your head like dandruff.
你知道我想做什么吗
You know what I wanted to do?
我想一把抓住那东西的阴毛  飞出去
I wanted to take that thing by the pubes and then fly outta there.
去其他游戏
To some other game.
去个新地方
To someplace new.
这不应该更新上去  而应该被销毁
This...this shouldn't be updated, it should be destroyed.
扔进你的点子箱吧
So stick that in your box.
我
I...
你们看上去棒极了
Wow, you guys look great.
-给你的  -谢谢
- Uh, here you go. - Thanks.
我该说清楚的...
It's...I should've clarified about...
没什么  我天天这么穿
Oh, come on. I wear this every day.
终于见到你们了
Yay, finally.
我听说了好多你们的事  我是莎拉
I've heard a lot about you guys. I'm Sara.
乔  别让客人站在门外
Joe, don't leave them in the hall.
-抱歉  请进  -大呆子
- Oh, sorry, come on in. - Big galoot.
我喜欢这个词  来自荷兰语
I love that word. It comes from the Dutch.
意思是苦役  海盗或皮条客
It means either galley slave or pirate or pimp.
如果我幸运的话  他三样都占了  对吗
But if I'm lucky, all three, right?
-想喝点什么吗  -好的  谢谢
- You guys want a drink? - Oh, yes, please.
金汤力  不放汤力水
Um, gin and tonic, hold the tonic.
真为你骄傲  我都要哭了
I'm so proud of you, I'm gonna cry.
所以我告诉他们  你们只有两个选择
So I told 'em, "You got two choices.
要么提升建议零售价  要么掩盖设备过时
Either bump the MSRP or cover our tooling overages."
当然了  并没有设备过时这回事
Of course, there were no tooling overages.
你个无赖  那可是我教你的
You son of a bitch, I taught you that move.
是啊  制造疾病  再卖给他们解药
Yeah, create the sickness, sell 'em the cure.
-仍然奏效  -这周我就是靠这个升职了
- It still works. - Hell, yeah, it got me a promotion this week.
-恭喜你  -这里不错啊
- Mm, congratulations. - So, this is cozy.
是啊  我们在奥斯汀有个更大的房子
Yeah, we got a bigger place in Austin.
这只是我家大作家的临时住所
This is just a pied-Terre for my auteur.
没错  我在努力完成一篇文章
Yeah, I'm trying to finish this article.
实际上  我是努力开始写
Well, actually, I'm trying to start it.
-是哪方面的呢  -贾维克人工心脏
- Oh, uh, about what? - The Jarvik artificial heart.
-那么很好写喽  -嗯
- Oh, so, um, nothing serious. - Well, yeah.
我朋友艾丽西娅负责设计  她是设计学教授
My friend Alicia's doing the layout. She's a professor of design.
他们一小时前就该到了
They should've been here an hour ago.
可能困在韦科市外了
Probably stuck outside Waco
试图用隐喻修补好漏气的轮胎
trying to fix a flat tire with a metaphor.
-谁不喜欢学术啊  -他们是可爱的怪人
- Gotta love academics. - Lovely people, total flakes.
乔  能帮我个忙吗
Joe, do you mind helping me for a second?
当然
Yeah.
-你现在是什么身份  -什么意思
- Who are you right now? - What do you mean?
不许你替我的朋友  我们的朋友
Don't you dare apologize for my friends,
这个公寓还有我表示不好意思
for our friends, for this apartment, or for me.
如果你今晚跟他们比够了
And if you're done dick measuring for the evening,
那你或许可以讲讲
then you might want to mention
你能晋升的真正原因
the real reason you got the promotion.
真相  你还记得吗
The truth. Do you remember that?
杏子也非常好吃
And the apricots are really good, too.
虽然蓝奶酪有点多了  但是...
Little heavy on the blue cheese, but...
好啦  刚才说到哪了
All right, where were we?
学术
Mm, academia.
嗯  听你的口气像是对它过敏似的
Right, you say that like it's a nut you're allergic to.
你知道吗  莎拉  我喜欢你
You know what, Sara? I like you.
我要给你个很有用的忠告
And I'm gonna give you a really good piece of advice.
别让他对你有保留
Don't let him hold out on you.
得了  乔
Come on, Joe.
你留着卡迪夫公司的钱干什么
What are you saving all that Cardiff money for?
共同基金  在特斯维拉湖上买船屋
Mutual funds? Houseboat on Lake Travis?
我没拿到卡迪夫的钱
I didn't get anything from Cardiff.
一分钱都没有
Not a penny.
把红酒递给我行吗
Pass the red?
视差        坦克大战          象棋      西洋跳棋      双陆棋
在线用户
你得过来一下
We need you out here.
现在就来
Like right now.
该死
Damn it!
只不过是个电脑游戏
It's a computer game, okay?
冷静一下  不会有事
Calm down. I'm sure it's nothing.
我看一下根文件
Let me just check the root file.
恶意软件攻击了我们的网络
Bad software hit our network.
正在覆盖我们的数据
It's overwriting our data.
我们的硬盘还是用户的
Our drives or the users'?
-都有  -刚刚覆盖了象棋
- Both. - It just ate chess.
-什么  -我们需要隔离没受到影响的机器
- What? - Hey, we need to quarantine all the unaffected machines.
-不行  -现在所有与网络连接的人...
- No! - Anyone connected right now...
-不行  -都容易受到攻击
- No! - ...is vulnerable.
我们还有在线的用户
We have users online.
我们不...我们要坚持住
We're not... we're staying up.
-开始攻击视差了  -天啊  太快了
- It's starting on "Parallax." - Christ, this thing is fast.
-第2章没了  -给唐娜打电话
- There goes chapter two. - Can somebody call Donna?
我们找不到她的号码
We couldn't find her number.
-什么  -哪里贴了张便条上有
- What? - It's on a Post-it somewhere.
天呐
Jesus.
你好  我找唐娜
Hi, can I speak to Donna?
什么  在哪啊
What? Where?
我是卡梅伦  她有留电话吗
It's Cameron. Did she leave a number?
听我说
Listen to me!
我得马上跟唐娜说话
I need to speak to Donna right away!
喂
Hello?
关掉
Shut it down.
整个网络吗
The whole network?
全部关掉
Everything, shut it all down.
或许你改变了他
Maybe you changed him.
他跟我前夫完全不同
No, he's nothing like my ex.
我以为你只喝啤酒呢
Thought you were strictly a beer guy.
我去年夏天喝了一瓶"桑希尔"
I had this bottle of "san-seer" at the mission last summer.
打开世界新大门了
It kind of rocked my world.
是桑塞尔
Sancerre.
桑管他妈的呢
Sans-who-gives-a-shit.
不错啊
That's good.
都值了  不是吗
It makes it all worthwhile, right?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
她现在忙得团团转
She's burning at both ends.
每天早上  我把她从沙发上抱下来
Every morning, I peel her off the couch,
安顿在床上
tuck her in.
算是轮到我主内了
My turn, I guess.
总之  你混得不错啊  很高兴见到你这样
Anyhow, you traded up. It's good to see you're doing so well.
你也不差
You, too.
你怎么没告诉我你被卡迪夫坑了
Why didn't you tell me you got screwed by Cardiff?
我觉得我能承受
Well, I thought I could live with it.
我会替你去找他的
Well, I'd have gone to him for you.
我虽然不会把自己的钱跟你分
I mean, I wouldn't have split my share or anything,
但至少也会替你说句话
but, you know, I would've spoken up.
我每天早上要去一间地下室上班
I report every morning to a basement.
我住在一间比我原来的房子不知小多少的公寓
I come home to an apartment that's smaller than my old bathroom.
但这样的生活
And yet if you offered me this version of my life
和你的分红
or your payout,
不管是多少  多少来着
whatever it was... how much was it?
83.81万美元
$838,100...
我会选择这个
I'd choose this.
我会选择她
I'd choose her.
-亲爱的  -嗯
- Honey? - Yeah?
抱歉  萝丝说穆特尼那边找我来着
Hey, I'm sorry. Rose says Mutiny's trying to reach me
我打过去  他们电话都占着线
and I called and their phone lines are all tied up.
我们该过去看看
I think we should head over there.
唐娜  问题严重吗
Oh, Donna, is it serious?
不  可能只是暴乱
No, it's probably just a riot,
大火  或巧克力糖吃多了
a massive fire, or a Goobers overdose.
乔  谢谢你今晚的招待
Joe, thank you for a lovely evening.
很高兴见到你
Well, it was good to see you.
抱歉要提前离开
Sorry we have to cut it short.
没事
It's okay.
慢慢喝桑塞尔吧
Enjoy the Sancerre.
莎拉  多谢邀请我们
Sara, thanks for having us.
天呐  我以为没完了呢
Oh, my God, I thought that would never end.
他跟她在一起做什么啊
What is he doing with her?
她又为什么跟他  你说呢
And vice versa, what do you think?
她是有救世主情节吗
She's got some sort of savior complex?
我不知道  我觉得她还蛮厉害的
I don't know. She seems impressive to me.
是啊  她父亲的大名肯定能提供不少机会
Yeah, well, I'm sure her father's name opens all kinds of doors.
乔很开心  也是个小奇迹了
Yeah, Joe's happy. Minor miracle.
当然了  他完全把她唬住了
Yeah, of course he is. He's got her completely snowed.
你今晚真美
Well, you look lovely tonight.
谢谢  老爸
Hey, uh, thank you, Pop.
现在大家都知道你坐在外面了
Now everyone knows you're out here.
你好吗  詹姆斯
How are you, James?
你出来之后不能打个电话吗
Couldn't have picked up a phone when you got out?
我想当面说
No, I wanted to say this in person.
天呐  开始了
Oh, jeez, here we go.
彩排晚宴很重要的
Look, the rehearsal dinner's a damn milestone,
坐好
so sit back...
闭上嘴
close your piehole.
有次圣诞节  我和詹姆斯妈妈看见他在屋顶上
"When his mother and I found James on the roof one Christmas,
拿着手电筒  准备了一堆问题  等着圣诞老人
waiting for Santa with a flashlight and a long list of questions,
我们就知道这孩子不怕挑战
we knew that our boy wasn't afraid of a challenge.
如今我们知道丽莎也是这样
And now we know Lisa isn't either."
-"此处应有笑声"  -真不错
- "Pause for laughter." - Oh, nice.
好吧
Okay.
詹姆斯第一次在小联盟比赛上三振出局时
"When James got his first strikeout in Little League,
我去做销售了
I was on a sales call.
他高中毕业时
When he graduated from high school,
我去坦帕开会了
I was at a conference in Tampa.
我知道  有时候他会觉得
I know there are times when it felt like
爸爸就是早上摸摸他的头
his father was nothing but a head rub in the morning
晚上门口一闪而过的人影
and a shadow in the door at night.
但今晚不会
But not this night.
今晚不会
Not tonight."
我能看看吗  我想拿给丽莎看
May I see it? I'd really like to show Lisa.
我不知道妈妈怎么跟你说的
Look, I don't know what Mom told you,
但我不生你的气
but I'm not angry at you.
我之前是生气  现在不了
I was, but I'm not.
听说你娶的姑娘不错
I hear you got yourself a hell of a gal, huh?
是啊
Aw, yeah.
我会请你们...哪天请你们来做客
Well, I'll have you over to the... over some night,
等我安顿好了的
you know, when I settle in.
好啊
Sure thing.
好了  老婆等着呢
All righty, well, wife's awaitin'.
这说起来好别扭
It's gonna feel weird saying that.
我老婆
"My wife."
多说说就习惯了
Well, it gets easier.
你明天来吧
Why don't you come tomorrow?
让一个释放犯坐在前排吗
What, an ex-con in the front pew?
你妈妈会炸的
Oh, your mother'd combust, for God's sake.
丽莎不会介意的
Well, Lisa wouldn't mind.
我也不会
Neither would I.
改天吧
Some other time.
嗯
All right.
照顾好这台爷爷车
Take care of this old thing.
我们用户加载的所有碟片都会受感染
Every disk our subscribers load will be infected.
我们得彻底重启
We're gonna have to do a clean reboot,
让用户不要上网
tell our users to stay offline
直到...
until...
我们寄出新软盘吗
We mail out new floppies?
全部寄新的  我们所有的游戏
Of everything. Every game that we make.
还得为毁了他们的其他软件赔偿他们
And reimburse them for ruining their other software.
他们的数据可能全被灭了
Chances are they've suffered total data extinction
而且会怪罪我们的
and they're gonna blame us.
天知道这下我们要彻底损失多少用户了
God knows how many subscribers we've lost for good.
小点心和鸡尾酒还算美味吗
Did you enjoy your finger food and cocktails?
卡梅伦  怎么回事
Cameron, what is this? What's going on?
一个恶意程序毁了我们的硬盘
A rogue program ate our drives.
抹去了我们所有的数据
Nuked all our data.
叫做索纳里斯
Something called Sonaris.
该死
Oh, shit.
你发送了
You sent it?
我...我们走之前
I... I mean, I... before we left...
等等  这是你写的
Stop. You wrote this?
不  我不知道他发送了
No, uh, I didn't know that he actually went ahead and sent it.
你不知道
You didn't know?
-你们是夫妻啊  -这什么意思...
- You're married to him. - What is that supposed...
我们是想帮你们找到所有实际用户
We were trying to help you map your network.
让我进去  我或许能帮忙
Look, let me in there, maybe I can help.
-你想帮我们  -对不起
- You want to help us? - I'm sorry, all right?
我给你们买点新硬盘
You know, I'll buy you some new drives.
关键不在于硬盘  混蛋
It's not the drives, asshole.
我们丢了游戏  原创游戏
We lost games. We lost original work.
不不  他根本不懂那个概念
No, no, no. He doesn't know what that is.
你不能别插手吗
You wouldn't just stay away?
你不能让我们做我们的吗
You couldn't just leave us to do our thing?
天呐  别那么自以为是了
Christ, get over yourself.
你讨厌我们的工作  因为它新奇  勇敢
I mean, which you hate because it's new and brave
而你只能站在外面往里看  你个卖身的
and because you're on the outside looking in, you sellout.
说话小心点
Watch your mouth.
而你老婆做的事
Meanwhile, your wife is doing things
你连想都想不出
that you couldn't even imagine.
-你还想把她扯进来吗  -戈登
- You want to bring her into this? - Okay. Gordon.
-你的租约谁签的  -戈登
- Who signs your lease? - Gordon!
你们的水电费谁偷偷付的
Who pays your water and electric behind your back?
你们还存在都是亏了唐娜
You know? Donna's the whole reason you haven't been condemned!
你肯定不知道  是吧
Bet you didn't know that, did you?
还有你  你  还有你  天才小丫头
Or you or you or you, Little Miss Girl Genius.
-这叫公司吗  -亲爱的
- You call this a company? - Honey...
是"呆子街噩梦"差不多
This is more like "Nightmare on Nerd Street"!
-亲爱的  -什么
- Hey, honey. - What?
你回家吧
Would you go home?
-唐娜  -回家吧  求你
- Donna. - Just go home, please.
先生
Sir.
那不是你的车啊
That's not your car.
有两台XT在运行
We've got two XTs up and running,
但游戏还断着线
but games are still down,
社区也是
Community, too.
我们得从备份恢复系统  彻底重装
We'll have to do a complete reinstall from backups.
你要我再道一次歉吗
Do you want me to apologize again?
这事我也很难过  我们是合伙人
This hurts me, too. We're partners.
得了
Please.
这是你的工作  唐娜  但是我的生活
This is your job, Donna, but it's my life.
我住这里  也就是说  我得一直
I live here, which means I'm always gonna catch
在这里面对此时此刻出现的麻烦
the shit that has to be dealt with right now
而你则在家里做冰棍
while you're at home making popsicles
-遛狗  -我们没养狗
- and walking the dog... - We don't have a dog.
或者让外人毁了我们的生意
...or letting an outside party liquefy our business.
而我都在这儿
I'm here.
你为什么没告诉我你要跟乔·麦克米伦吃饭
Why didn't you tell me you were having dinner with Joe MacMillan?
我觉得你会为此生我气的
Well, I was pretty sure you'd hold it against me.
答对有奖
Ding, give the lady a prize.
-只是一顿饭而已  -回你丈夫身边去吧
- It was just dinner. - Go home to your husband.
还有  唐娜
Oh, and, Donna.
你再背着我  偷偷用自己的钱
If you ever put another dime of your own money into Mutiny again
给穆特尼垫费  你就被解雇了
behind my back, you're fired.
-要我送你回家吗  -不了  谢谢
- You want a ride? - No, thanks.
我能做什么
What can I do?
在线用户
国际象棋             西洋跳棋              双陆棋
视差                     坦克大战
-卡梅伦  -等一下
- Hey, uh, Cameron? - Huh? Oh, just give me a second.
好了  卡梅伦  呼吸
Okay, Cameron, just breathe, okay?
-我在呼吸  -没事的
- I am breathing. - Okay, hey.
卡梅伦  呼吸  过来
Cameron, breathe. Come here, come here.
过来  坐下
Come here. Come here. Sit down.
就点头或摇头  好吗  需要我叫医生吗
Just nod or shake your head, okay? Should I call a doctor?
你用什么药了吗
Okay, are you on any medication?
捏  再用力点  很好
Squeeze, squeeze. Harder, harder... good.
视差
"Parallax."
第3章  第7关  四巫师洞穴
Chapter three, level seven. The cave of the four wizards.
-你怎么...听我说  -什么
- How do you... focus. - What?
怎么把龙蛋带过峡谷
How do you get the dragon's egg across the chasm?
-什么  -如果你跳
- What... - 'Cause if you jump,
蛋会掉  对吧  有条绳索桥
you're gonna drop it, right? And there's a rope bridge.
但拿着蛋  你就过重了
But with the egg, you're too heavy.
卡梅伦  怎么办
So, Cameron, what do you do?
不知道  退回去
I don't know. You go back.
没错  退回去
That's right, that's right. You go back.
退回去  转身  回到洞穴里
You go back. You turn around, you go back inside,
面对第四名巫师
and you face the fourth wizard.
对吧
Right?
只有把蛋在他胸口上砸开
And then only by cracking the egg in his chest
才能让他重新变成人
can you make him human again.
好
Okay.
这就是我怀念视差的地方
That's what I'm gonna miss about "Parallax."
最初的那几章
Those early chapters,
每个陷阱都有奖赏
how every trap had a reward,
每个出口其实都是入口
every exit was actually an entrance.
让我觉得像《绿野仙踪》一样
You know, the whole thing made me feel like "The Wizard of Oz."
但还要更好  因为你
But it was better because you were really like...
像是进入了电影里
like inside the movie, you know?
驾驭气球  跑过罂粟田
Running those balloons, running through those poppy fields?
感觉像真的一样
It was like it was real.
我要放手了
I'm gonna let go, okay?
嗯
Yeah.
我去给你拿点水
I'm gonna get you some water.
别走开  好吗
Don't go anywhere, okay?
有多严重
How bad is it?
很严重
It's bad.
我该多测试几次的
I should've tested it more.
我...我一激动起来就...
I just... I got excited or...
我也说不好  我该告诉你的
I don't know. I should have told you.
不
No.
是我没管
No, I let it happen.
我没阻止你
I didn't stop you.
究竟是什么问题
What exactly was the issue?
对不起
Oh, sorry.
嗯  我也想搞明白呢
Well, that's what I'm trying to find out.
嗯  等等
Yeah, hold on. Hold on.
等等
Hold on.
早啊
Morning.
真有意思
Boy, that's funny. Yeah.
去主机室见我
Meet me in the mainframe room.
-我就好了  -马上
- I'm almost done. - Now.
这些机器
These machines.
跟我们一样上下班
They work the same shift as us.
是啊  朝九晚五  怎么了
Yep, 9:00 to 5:00. Why?
价值数百万的机器
Millions of dollars of hardware
每天闲坐16个小时
sitting unused for 16 hours a day.
到底什么事
What's this about?
是突破口
A way in.
-什么  -没事了
- What? - Never mind.
那我回去工作了
Back to work, then?
是  先生
Yes, sir.